Guide to the Julian Sorell Huxley Papers, 1899-1980 MS 050
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series III: General Correspondence, 1904-1980, 257238
  - July - December 1922, 257530 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 1922, n.d.; 19020-1922, n.d., 257529 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - January - June 1923, 257528 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - July - December 1923, 257527 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 1923, n.d.; 1923-1924, 257526 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - January - June 1924, 257525 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - July - December 1924, 257524 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 1924, n.d.; 1923-1924, 257523 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - January - March 1925, 257522 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - April - July 1925, 257521 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - August - December 1925, 257520 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 1925, n.d.; 1923-1925, n.d.; 1924-1925, n.d., 257519 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - January - June 1926, 257518 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - July - December 1926, 257517 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - 1926, n.d., 257516 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - January - June 1927, 257515 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - July - December 1927, 257514 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - 1927, n.d.; 1920-1927, 257513 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - January - June 1928, 257512 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - July - December 1928, 257511 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - 1928, n.d., 257510 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - January - June 1929, 257509 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - July - December 1929, 257508 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - 1929 n.d.; 1927-1929, 1928-1929, 257507 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - 1920-1929 n.d., 257506 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - January - June 1930, 257505 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - July - December 1930, 257504 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - 1930 n.d., 257503 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - January - December 1931, 257502 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - 1931 n.d., 1930-1931, 257501 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - January - December 1932, 257500 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - 1932 n.d., 257499 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - January - December 1933, 257498 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - 1933 n.d., 257497 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - January - July 1934, 257496 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - August - December 1934, 257495 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - 1934 n.d.; 1930-1934; 1931-1934; 1933-1934, 257494 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - January - June 1935, 257493 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - July - December 1935, 257492 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - 1935 n.d.; 1934-1935 n.d., 257491 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - January - March 1936, 257490 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - April - August 1936, 257489 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - September - December 1936, 257488 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - 1936 n.d.; 1924-1936, 257487 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - January - March 1937, 257486 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - April - June 1937, 257485 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - July - December 1937, 257484 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - 1937 n.d.; [1930-1937], 257483 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - January - February 1938, 257482 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - March 1938, 257481 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - April - August 1938, 257480 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - September - December 1938, 257479 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - 1938 n.d., 257478 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - January - June 1939, 257477 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - July - December 1939, 257476 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - 1939 n.d.; 1938-1939, 257475 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - 1930-1939 n.d., 257474 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - January - February 1940, 257473 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - March - April 1940, 257472 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - May - June 1940, 257471 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - July - August 1940, 257470 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - September - October 1940, 257469 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - November - December 1940, 257468 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - 1939-1940; 1940 n.d., 257467 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - January - February 1941, 257466 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - March - April 1941, 257465 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - May - June 1941, 257464 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - July - August 1941, 257463 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - September - October 1941, 257462 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - November - December 1941, 257461 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - 1941, n.d., 257460 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - January - March 1942, 257459 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - April - June 1942, 257458 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - July - September 1942, 257457 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - October - December 1942, 257456 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - 1942 n.d., 257455 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - [1935-1942?], 257454 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - January - June 1943, 257453 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - July - December 1943, 257452 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - 1943 n.d.; 1941-1943, 257451 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - 1944, 257450 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - 1944 n.d., 257449 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - 1945, 257448 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - 1945 n.d.; 1940-1945, 257447 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - 1946, 257446 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - 1946 n.d., 257445 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - 1947, 257444 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - 1947 n.d., 257443 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - January - June 1948, 257442 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - July - December 1948, 257441 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - 1948 n.d., 257440 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - January - March 1949, 257439 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - April - June 1949, 257438 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - July - August 1949, 257437 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - September - December 1949, 257436 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - 1949 n.d.; 1940s n.d., 257435 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - January - February 1950, 257434 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - March - April 1950, 257433 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - May - June 1950, 257432 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - July - August 1950, 257431 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - September - October 1950, 257430 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - November - December 1950, 257429 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - 1950 n.d., 257428 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - January - February 1951, 257427 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - March - April 1951, 257426 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - May - June 1951, 257425 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - July - August 1951, 257424 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - September - October 1951, 257423 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - November - December 1951, 257422 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - 1951 n.d., 257421 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - January - March 1952, 257420 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - April - June 1952, 257419 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - July - August 1952, 257418 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - September - October 1952, 257417 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - November - December 1952, 257416 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - 1952 n.d., 257415 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - January - February 1953, 257414 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - March - April 1953, 257413 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - May - June 1953, 257412 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - July - August 1953, 257411 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - September - October 1953, 257410 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - November - December 1953, 257409 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - 1953 n.d., 257408 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - January - March 1954, 257407 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - April - June 1954, 257406 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - July - August 1954, 257405 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - September - October 1954, 257404 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - November - December 1954, 257403 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - 1954 n.d., 257402 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - January - February 1955, 257401 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - March - April 1955, 257400 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - May - June 1955, 257399 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - July - August 1955, 257398 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - September - October 1955, 257397 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - November - December 1955, 257396 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - 1955 n.d., 257395 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - January - February 1956, 257394 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - March - April 1956, 257393 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - May - June 1956, 257392 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - July - August 1956, 257391 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - September - October 1956, 257390 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - November - December 1956, 257389 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - 1956 n.d., 257388 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - January - February 1957, 257387 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - March - April 1957, 257386 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - May 1957, 257385 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - June 1957, 257384 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - July - August 1957, 257383 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - September - October 1957, 257382 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - November - December 1957, 257381 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - 1957 n.d., 257380 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - January 1, 1958, 257379 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - January 1958, 257378 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - February - March 1958, 257377 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - April - May 1958, 257376 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - June - July 1958, 257375 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - August - September 1958, 257374 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - October 1958, 257373 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - November 1958, 257372 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - December 1958, 257371 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - 1958 n.d., 257370 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - January - February 1959, 257369 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - March - April 1959, 257368 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - May - June 1959, 257367 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - July - August 1959, 257366 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - September - October 1959, 257365 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - November - December 1959, 257364 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - 1959 n.d.; 1950s, 257363 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - January 1960, 257362 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - February 1960, 257361 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - March 1960, 257360 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - April 1960, 257359 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - May 1960, 257358 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - June 1960, 257357 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - July 1960, 257356 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - August 1960, 257355 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - September 1960, 257354 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - October 1960, 257353 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - November 1960, 257352 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - December 1960, 257351 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - 1960 n.d., 257350 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - January 1961, 257349 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - February 1961, 257348 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - March 1961, 257347 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - April 1961, 257346 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - May 1961, 257345 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - June 1961, 257344 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - July 1961, 257343 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - August 1961, 257342 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - September 1961, 257341 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - October 1961, 257340 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - November 1961, 257339 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - December 1961, 257338 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - 1961 n.d., 257337 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - January - February 1962, 257336 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - March 1962, 257335 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - April - March 1962, 257334 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - June 1962, 257333 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - July - August 1962, 257332 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - September 1962, 257331 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - October 1962, 257330 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - November - December 1962, 257329 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - 1962 n.d.; [1961 or 1962?], 257328 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - January 1963, 257327 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - February 1963, 257326 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - March 1963, 257325 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - April 1963, 257324 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - May 1963, 257323 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - June 1963, 257322 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - July 1963, 257321 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - August 1963, 257320 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - September 1963, 257319 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - October 1963, 257318 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - November 1963, 257317 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - December 1963, 257316 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - 1963 n.d., 257315 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - January 1964, 257314 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - February 1964, 257313 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - March 1964, 257312 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - April 1964, 257311 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - May 1964, 257310 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - June 1964, 257309 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - July 1964, 257308 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - August 1964, 257307 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - September 1964, 257306 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - October 1964, 257305 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - November 1964, 257304 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - December 1964, 257303 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - 1964 n.d., 257302 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - 1-15 January 1965, 257301 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - 16-31 January 1965, 257300 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - February 1965, 257299 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - 1-15 March 1965, 257298 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - 16-31 March 1965, 257297 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - April 1965, 257296 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - May 1965, 257295 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - June 1965, 257294 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - July 1965, 257293 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - August 1965, 257292 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - September 1965, 257291 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - October 1965, 257290 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - November 1965, 257289 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - December 1965, 257288 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - 1965 n.d.; 1964-1965, 257287 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - January 1966, 257286 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - February - March 1966, 257285 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - April - June 1966, 257284 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - July - September 1966, 257283 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - October - December 1966, 257282 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - 1966 n.d., 257281 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - January - May 1967, 257280 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - June 1967, 257279 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - July - December 1967, 257278 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - 1967 n.d., 257277 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - January - December 1968; 1968 n.d., 257276 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - January - July 1969, 257275 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - August - December 1969; 1969 n.d., 257274 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - 1960-1969; 1960s n.d., 257273 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - January - June 1970, 257272 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - July - September 1970, 257271 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - October - November 1970, 257270 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - December 1970, 257269 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - 1970 n.d., 257268 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - January - March 1971, 257267 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - April - June 1971, 257266 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - July - August 1971, 257265 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - September - October 1971, 257264 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - November - December 1971, 257263 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - 1971 n.d., 257262 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - January - March 1972, 257261 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - April - June 1972, 257260 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - July - September 1972, 257259 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - October - December 1972, 257258 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - 1972 n.d.; 1971-1972, 257257 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - January - March 1973, 257256 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - April - June 1973, 257255 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - July - September 1973, 257254 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - October - December 1973, 257253 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - 1973 n.d., 257252 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - January - June 1974, 257251 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - July - December 1974, 257250 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - 1974 n.d., 257249 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - 1975, 257248 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - 1976; 1976 n.d., 257247 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - 1977, 257246 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - 1978, 257245 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - 1979, 257244 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - 1970-1979, 257243 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - 1980, 257242 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Selected correspondents A-K, No date:; 257241 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Selected Correspondents L-Z, No date:; 257240 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - No date, 257239 (Box 47, Folder 3)
- Series IV: Journals, Diaries, and Notebooks, 257176
  This series contains pocket diaries, journals, notes, exercise books and calendars kept by Huxley from 1910 until his death, arranged in chronological order. They are rich in information of both personal and scientific nature. From his youth, there are notebooks of biological drawings, bird-watching notes, class notes and essays. The pocket diaries of the later period contain appointments, itineraries and observations about activities in which he was involved at various times. Those notebooks from Huxley's Oxford and University of London period also contain faculty lists and university schedules.
  Of particular interest are the journals kept by Huxley throughout his life which provide a wealth of biographical material. Other journals which relate to his travels are found in the TRAVEL MATERIALS series. Notebooks containing drafts of his autobiography are found in Series V: Manuscripts, Typescripts, and Notes.
  Pre-1909 materials are found in Series I: Early Materials.
  - 1910-1916, 257237 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - 1913, 257236 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - 1915, 257235 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - "Texas Birds", 257234 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - 1917, 257233 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - 1921-1927, 257232 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - 1928-1929, 257231 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - 1917-1919, 257230 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - 1930-1931, 257229 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - 1932-1933, 257228 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - 1934, 257227 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - 1934-1936, 257226 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - 1937-1939, 257225 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - "Early Autumn", 1939; 257224 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - 1936, 257223 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - 1940-1941, 257222 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - 1941-1942, 257221 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - 1942, 257220 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - 1943-1945, 257219 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - "Paris 1945", 257218 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - 1940-1945, 257217 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Sketchbook, 1944; 257216 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - 1948, 257215 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - 1947, 257214 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - 1947-1949, 257213 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - 1946-1948, 257212 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - 1949, 257211 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - 1950, 257210 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - 1951, 257209 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - 1953, 257208 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - 1953-1954, 257207 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - 1955, 257206 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - 1956, 257205 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - 1956, 257204 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - 1957, 257203 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - 1958, 257202 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - 1959, 257201 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - 1960, 257200 (Box 53, Folder 1-2)
  - 1960-1962, 257199 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - 1961, 257198 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - 1962, 257197 (Box 53, Folder 5-6)
  - 1963, 257196 (Box 54, Folder 1-2)
  - 1964, 257195 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - 1964-1965, 257194 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - 1965, 257193 (Box 54, Folder 5-8)
  - 1966, 257192 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - 1967-1969, 257191 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - 1960s, 257190 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - 1970-1974, 257189 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Undated, 257188 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Undated, 257187 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Embryology (Invertebrate, Vertebrate) Notebooks, 257186 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - 1910, 257185 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Birdwatching Notes, 257184 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - "Notes and Queries", 257183 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Biological Drawings, 257182 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Notebook, 257181 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Biology Notebook, 1912; 257180 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - General Biology Notebook, 257179 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Essays, 1916-1917; 257178 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - "Oxford Undergraduate Notebook", 257177 (Box 56, Folder 9)
- Series V: Manuscripts, Typescripts, and Notes, 256850
  This series contains notes, manuscripts and typescripts written by Huxley between 1910 and 1974. This series is particularly rich because it details the development of his thought and conveys the variety of his interests. There are poems and short stories written when he was a young man, notes on scientific work and classroom lectures given during the period when he taught biology. (N.B. Among these are a series of lectures he prepared while at Rice.) The series also contains manuscripts and/ or typed copies of articles, book reviews, drafts of letters to editors and public lectures. Of special interest are the manuscripts for the Romanes Lecture (1943), the Kalinga Prize Speech (1953), the Lasker Award Address (1959) and the John Danz Lecture (1962); and those of The Science of Life, The Humanist Frame, From an Antique Land and both volumes of Huxley's autobiography, Memories.
  The manuscripts, typescripts and notes are in chronological order. However, many of the notes and manuscript fragments are on undated scraps of paper and some are almost illegible. Therefore, although the greatest care has been taken to ascertain the date for each fragment, it was impossible to accurately place each manuscript or note. The researcher should bear this in mind when using these materials.
  - Notes, 1910; 257175 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Notes, 1910; 257174 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript, Lecture Notes, 1911-1912; 257173 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - "OHO Warburg Notes", 1912-1913; 257172 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Texas Observations, 1913-1914; 257171 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Rice Lectures 1-6, 1914-1916; 257170 (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Notes, 1915; 257169 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - 1912-1915, 257168 (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Manuscripts, Notes, 1915-1916; 257167 (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - "America", 1916; 257166 (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - "Vicious Circle", 257165 (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Notes, 1917; 257164 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - 1917-1918, 257163 (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - 1917-1918, 257162 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - "Naples at Christmas", 1918; 257161 (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - 1918, 257160 (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - 1918, 257159 (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - 1919, 257158 (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Notes: "Late in War?", circa 1930; 257157 (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - 1917-1919, 257156 (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - Poetry, 1910-1919; 257155 (Box 58, Folder 10)
  - Undateable material, 1916-1919; 257154 (Box 58, Folder 11)
  - Lecture Notes, "The Principles of Biology", 1920s; 257153 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - 1920, 257152 (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - 1921-1922, 257151 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - 1922, 257150 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - 1923, 257149 (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - 1923, 257148 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Limericks & Poetry Games, 1925; 257147 (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - 1923-1925, 257146 (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - Notes for unwritten book on bird courtship, 1925; 257145 (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - 1926-1929, 257144 (Box 59, Folder 10)
  - 1928, 257143 (Box 59, Folder 11)
  - Untitled MS -, 1920s; 257141 (Box 59, Folder 12)
  - Undated 1920s, 257140 (Box 59, Folder 13)
  - Notes, 1928; 257139 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - "The heavens declare the glory of God", 1928; 257138 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Undateable material -, 1920s; 257137 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Undateable -, 1920s; 257136 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Poetry, 1920s; 257135 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - 1920s, 257134 (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - "Evolution", 1920s; 257133 (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - "Research", 1920s; 257132 (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - "Fragments", 1920s; 257131 (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - "Notes for Questionnaire", 1920s; 257130 (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - 1920s, 257129 (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - Notes - Undateable, 1920s; 257128 (Box 60, Folder 12)
  - Manuscript - "Science of Life", 257127 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript - "Science of Life", 257126 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Science of Life (Outline), 257125 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Science of Life, 1927; 257124 (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Zoology/ Biology Curriculum, 1930; 257123 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - 1930-1931, 257122 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - 1932, 257121 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - The Belief in Survival, 1932; 257120 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Poetry, The Captive Shrew, 1932; 257119 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - 1933, 257118 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Man's Place in the Universe, 1933; 257117 (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - 1934, 257116 (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - Westmann Islands, 1934; 257115 (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - Africa, 1934; 257114 (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - 1935, 257113 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - 1937, 257112 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Transcripts, 1937; 257111 (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - 1938, 257110 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - 1939, 257109 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Notes for Halifax Interview, 1939; 257108 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Sheldrake, 1939; 257107 (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Man's Place in Nature and Uniqueness of Man, 1930s; 257106 (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Poetry, 1930s; 257105 (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - Undateable, 1930s; 257104 (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - Notes, 1930s; 257103 (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - Notes, 1930s; 257102 (Box 64, Folder 12)
  - 1940, 257101 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - 1941, 257100 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - MSS from Whipsnade, Nature and Art, 1941; 257099 (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Typescripts, 1942; 257098 (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Unity in the U.S.A., 1942; 257097 (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - A Philosophy of Life and its Applications, 1943; 257096 (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - 1943, 257095 (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - Art as a Social Function, 1943; 257094 (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - Romanes Lecture, June 11, 1943; 257093 (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - 1944, 257092 (Box 65, Folder 10)
  - Commission under Walter Elliot to West Africa, 1944; 257091 (Box 65, Folder 11)
  - Jumping the Centuries - Mass Education, 1944; 257090 (Box 65, Folder 12)
  - West Africa Notes, 1943-1945; 257089 (Box 65, Folder 13)
  - Atomic Energy, 1945; 257088 (Box 65, Folder 14)
  - 1945, 257087 (Box 65, Folder 15)
  - 1946, 257086 (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Unesco notes, 1946; 257085 (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - File on Art, 1946; 257084 (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Census - Taking in the Wild, 1946; 257083 (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - 1947, 257082 (Box 66, Folder 5)